Johnson Shan

Toronto, On, Canada

(416) 627-5761

johnsonshan951101@gmail.com

in linkedin.com/in/johnson-shan-b9a373168

github.com/JohnsonShan

iohnsonshan-portfolio.netlifv.app

Summary

Software engineer with 4-years of full stack web development experience specializing in Python, Node.js and React.js. Certified in Cloud solutions and DevOps solutions by both Microsoft Azure and Amazon Web Services (AWS). Excel in data structures and algorithms, having successfully completed 400 LeetCode problems. Known for a strong problem-solving ability and a "get things done" attitude. Committed to continuous learning and growth. Seeking new challenges and opportunities to further enhance skills and contribute to innovative software solutions.

Work Experience

Manpower Services Limited Software Engineer

08/2022 - 06/2023

- Responsible for system integration **APIs development** between websites, mobile apps, CRM, ERP, etc. using Python, Node.js, Amazon Web Services (AWS), Microsoft Azure etc.
- Built integration APIs for invoicing service and reduced manual workload by 50%.
- Worked on on-premises to cloud migration with third-party vendors, successfully migrating 100+ APIs and increasing the service's scalability and availability by 100%.
- Implemented a high-availability (HA) architecture and disaster recovery (DR) plan to increase service availability, achieve a 99.95% SLA, downsized idle resources, and set up auto-scaling policies to reduce hosting costs by 50%.
- Implemented Azure Active Directory integration, centralized identity and access management(IAM), reduced manual workload by 80%.
- Implemented **DevOps CI/CD** pipelines using GitHub Actions, Jenkins, and SonarQube, resulting in a 50% reduction in deployment time and a 25% increase in team productivity.

HomePlus Ltd. Software Engineer

10/2021 - 08/2022

- Responsible for API development, for an E-commerce platform using Python, Node.js, Express, Amazon Web Services (AWS), EC2, S3, API Gateway, CloudWatch, ElastiCache Redis, DynamoDB, etc.
- Integrated with the content management system(CMS) Squidex.
- Write API documentation using Swagger, conduct stress tests using JMeter, and set up API monitoring using Postman.
- Reduced hosting and license costs by \$200,000 CAD through a successful migration.
- Enhanced **Product Searching APIs**, using Algolia and Redis, reducing the response time from 5s to within 1s.

Web Developer Fimmick Ltd. 10/2020 - 10/2021

- Responsible for Web development, including both **Frontend and Backend**, integration with third party API, using **React.js**, **Next.js**, **Python**, **Node.js**, **Tailwind**, **jQuery**, **Bootstrap** etc.
- Implemented data services using **Google Analytics and API Webhooks**, export the data to a reporting database, and generate CSV reports.
- Built messaging service for schedule push notifications, SMS, and marketing email for marketing events
- Built 10+ campaign websites for famous MNCs such as Abbott, Nestle, Coca-Cola, and McDonald's.
- Built a customer loyalty web app to serve 10,000+ customers.
- Implemented a **2FA** (two-factor authentication) feature.

Developer The Pacific Insurance Co., Ltd. 10/2019 - 10/2020

- Responsible for developing quotations services and report services using Java Spring Boot.
- Built a customer-facing premium calculator.
- Automated the quotation process and improved the processing time by 50%.

Education

Bachelor of Engineering	City University of Hong Kong	2020
Major in Electronic Information Engineering		

Certifications

Microsoft Certified: Azure Solutions Architect Expert	Microsoft	2023
Microsoft Certified: DevOps Engineer Expert	Microsoft	2023
Microsoft Certified: Azure Administrator Associate	Microsoft	2023
AWS Certified Solutions Architect – Associate	Amazon Web Services	2022

Skills & Tools

Programming Language Python, Node.js, Java, PHP, Typescript, Javascript, HTML, CSS Framework Django, Express, Spring Boot, Laravel, React.js, Next.js, Gatsby,

Tailwind, ¡Query, Bootstrap

Database PostgreSQL, MySQL, SQL Server, Redis, MongoDb Atlas, DynamoDB, Devops GitHub, GitHub Action, Azure DevOps, Jenkins, Ansible, Terraform

Methodologies Scrum, Agile

Others RESTful, GraphQL, Docker, Microservices, Kubernetes, Serverless,

Jira, ITIL, Postman, Jmeter, Swagger, DR, HA, CICD, CloudWatch, S3,

EC2, Lambda, Unit Test, Azure Active Directory, Oauth

Languages English, Chinese (Cantonese and Mandarin)